SAMIR THAPA

sameerthapa159@gmail.com

(334) 492-6746

109 W Normal Avenue (Troy, Alabama)

Website-SamirThapa

Github-SamirThapa

Linkedin-SamirThapa

Software Developer, has 2 years of experience in developing software. Clear understanding of programming logic and algorithms and knowledge in multiple programming languages. Also have great communication and organization skills. Motivated to learn, grow and excel

SKILLS

- Programming Languages
 - Python (Django)
 - JS (React, Node)
 - \circ (
 - o C++
- Version Control
 - Git
- Database Knowledge
 - Firebase
 - SQL
 - MongoDB
- Algorithms and Data Structures
- Communication
- Team Work

WORK EXPERIENCE

AAJPROPERTY LLC – Software Developer

September 2021 - December 2023

Kathmandu, Nepal

- Developed main website i.e. aajproperty.com by using react and node which helps users to see and buy available property
- Worked within agile team to create application called brokers terminal which helps users to search and buy the property and also helps to link the registered brokers.
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability
- Created database schemas of all the property by using MongoDB
- Cooperate with designers to create clean interfaces and interactive websites

Prodigy Technosys Pvt.Ltd – Junior Software Developer

May 2021 - August 2021

Kathmandu, Nepal

- Developed website for the shoes shop which shows the available shoes in the shop and can also buy and order shoes from the website
- Made interactive website and implemented RESTful APIs in Django
- Worked with group to create various software by using python
- Participated in code reviews

PROJECTS

Project Stack

- Built a full-stack web app that recommend users projects that matches their interest and skillsets
- PDF of the project is taken as the dataset and converted to the CSV file and then used K- means algorithm to create clusters of the projects
- Cosine Similarities is used to compare users interest and clusters
- Contains various functionality like login, registration, upload project, edit profile and download files

E-Class

- Built android application for students using Kotline
- Users can get the information about the college like class schedule, notices and can also discuss on the discussion section
- Contains admin control which is only accessible to the admin who can post assignments, notices and routine which is done through web
- Contains login, registration, notices, notes, assignment and discussion section

Disaster Tweet Classification

- A simple model to predict whether the tweet is about disaster
- Used Python, pandas, numpy
- CSV file is taken as the input and then model is created by training those data and at last testing is done to validate the model
- Ridge Regression is used to predict whether the tweet about disaster or not

EDUCATION

Troy University - M.S., Computer Science

2024 - Current Troy, Al

Kantipur Engineering College - B.S., Computer Engineering

2016 - 2022 Lalitpur, Nepal

CERTIFICATES

- Training Certificate of Python Django
- Intern Certificate of junior web developer
- Work experience of two years.